Costa Rican law is an absolute maze. I'm
sweating over it a little bit. One thing
I wish I would have known before
starting a business in Costa Rica is how
complicated the legal system of Costa
Rica is. They just passed a new law, law
10,597.
Basically, it says you have to register
an official email on your Costa Rican
corporation in order to receive all
notifications [music]
from the government. And there's a
deadline on it, June 4th, 2026, 2 weeks
away. If you don't register your email,
the corporation is basically frozen.
Can't change officers, you can't change
directors, you can't grant powers of
attorney, you can't change your bylaws.
It's actually a pretty big problem. The
company is still in effect, but you're
basically stuck. In order to register
your email, you're going to have to get
a Costa Rican [music] attorney to do it,
which is kind of a problem because Costa
Rica has more lawyers per capita than
any country on planet Earth, and a lot
of them will tell you different things.
Thus far, I've consulted three Costa
[music] Rican attorneys and two
accountants. I'm sweating over it a
little bit, but I'm going to make the
deadline, and I wanted to let you know
[music] because Costa Rican law is an
absolute maze. You have to have a very
good attorney, you have to stay on top
of things, or else you're going to get
frozen. A little update on law 10,597
from Costa Rica for all my expats over
there trying to live the dream, too, cuz
living the dream is not always what
[music] it seems.